[triumphant music]
[胜利的音乐]
*
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[laughing]
[笑]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
Ahh. [grunts]
啊。 [咕哝]
Phew!
唷！
- What's that?
- 那是什么？
- Looks like a box.
- 看起来像一个盒子。
- Wonder who it belongs to.
- 想知道它属于谁。
[grunts]
Maybe it says on the other side.
[咕哝]
或许另一边也这么说。
both: Nope.
两人：没有。
- Oh, look, it's open.
- 哦，看，它已经打开了。
- It is?
- 这是？
- [grunts]
Yup.
- [咕哝]
是的。
- Ooh.
- 哦。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
It's--
它是 -
it's--
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
It's stuff!
是东西啊！
- [laughs]
Oh, I knew it!
- [笑]
哦，我知道了！
But what does this stuff do?
但这东西有什么作用呢？
[both grunt]
[两人咕哝]
both: Hmm.
两人：嗯。
- Ah, this must be for getting
books off the top shelf.
- 啊，这一定是为了得到
书架上的书。
- Hey! [laughs]
- 嘿！ [笑]
Oh! [groans]
哦！ [呻吟]
Hmm. Mm.
唔。毫米。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Wow.
哇。
This is must be
a whipped cream holder.
这必须是
鲜奶油架。
Mmm.
嗯。
[moans]
[呻吟声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Ah!
Patrick, are you okay?
- 啊！
帕特里克，你还好吗？
[moaning]
[呻吟]
Yum.
嗯。
- Meow.
- This must be
- 喵。
- 这一定是
a portable snail bed.
便携式蜗牛床。
* Rock-a-bye Gary
*摇滚再见加里
- I wanna try!
- 我想尝试！
[grunts]
- Meow.
[咕哝]
- 喵。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[snores]
[打鼾]
- Aww. [chuckles]
- 哇。 [笑声]
[pleasant music]
[悦耳的音乐]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Oh, it may have taken you
all morning, Squidward,
哦，它可能已经带走了你
整个早上，章鱼哥，
but this is a meal
fit for a king.
但这是一顿饭
适合国王。
[bell dings]
Oh.
[铃声]
哦。
My croque-madame is ready.
我的法式三明治夫人准备好了。
What the--
[grunts]
什么是——
[咕哝]
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
[growls]
[咆哮]
SpongeBob! Patrick!
海绵宝宝！帕特里克！
What do you two
think you're--
你们两个做什么
认为你是——
wow.
哇。
- [laughs]
- [humming]
- [笑]
- [嗡嗡声]
both: Hiyah!
- [laughs]
两人：嗨！
- [笑]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- My begonias!
- 我的秋海棠！
What are you lunk heads doing
with all this equipment?
你们这些笨蛋在做什么
有这些设备吗？
both: Equipment?
两人：装备？
- You don't know
what this stuff is?
- 你不知道
这东西是什么？
both: Mm-mmm. Mm-mmm.
两人：嗯嗯。嗯嗯。
- This is a soccer ball...
- 这是一个足球...
that is a tennis racket,
and these...
那是一个网球拍，
还有这些...
are a couple of morons.
是一对白痴。
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
Now, be quiet!
现在，安静点！
And clean up
all of your sports junk!
并清理干净
你所有的运动垃圾！
both: What's a "sportz"?
两者：什么是“sportz”？
- [groans]
Sports are games
- [呻吟]
体育就是游戏
you play for points.
你玩游戏是为了积分。
The points determine
the winner of the game.
点决定
游戏的获胜者。
- Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh! Oh!
I love games!
- 哦！哦！哦！哦！哦！
我喜欢游戏！
- Me too!
You must know a lot
- 我也是！
你一定知道很多
about "sportz," Squidward.
关于《sportz》，《章鱼哥》。
Will you teach us
how to play?
你会教我们吗
怎么玩？
- I can't think of anything
I'd rather do less than--
-我什么也想不出来
我宁愿做的比——
[twinkling]
[闪烁]
- Now now, Squidward.
You need to help them.
-现在现在，章鱼哥。
你需要帮助他们。
Played incorrectly,
sports can be very dangerous.
玩错了，
运动可能非常危险。
- Yeah, he's right.
You should teach 'em
- 是的，他是对的。
你应该教他们
to play wrong,
'cause it's payback time.
玩错了，
因为现在是回报的时候了。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Let 'em have it,
right between the eyes.
让他们拥有吧
就在眼睛之间。
- You know, on second thought,
I'd be happy to teach you
- 你知道，再想一想，
我很乐意教你
all about sports,
SpongeBob.
关于运动的一切，
海绵宝宝。
[evil chuckle]
[邪恶的笑声]
All right, the object
of this game
好吧，对象
这个游戏的
is to throw the horseshoe
around the stick.
就是扔马蹄铁
棍子周围。
- Ah, seems easy enough.
- 啊，看起来很简单。
- Sure, but you have to do it...
blindfolded.
- 当然可以，但是你必须这么做......
蒙住眼睛。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Um, do we throw now?
嗯，我们现在扔吗？
- Yes.
- At the same time?
- 是的。
- 同时？
- Yes! Throw it
at the same time. Throw.
- 是的！扔掉它
同时。扔。
- Hiyah!
-嗨！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Ow!
- 噢！
Aw, we didn't hit the sticks.
Did we do bad?
哦，我们没有撞到棍子。
我们做坏事了吗？
- My face hurts.
- 我的脸很痛。
- Oh, no, no, no.
You both did good.
- 哦，不，不，不。
你们俩都做得很好。
Pain is--
uh, worth points.
痛苦是——
嗯，值得积分。
You know the phrase,
"no pain, no gain."
你知道这句话，
“没有痛苦，就没有收获。”
- [laughs]
- [笑]
I want pain points!
我要痛点！
[grunts]
[horse whinnies]
[咕哝]
[马嘶声]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Yeah, that's great.
- 是的，那太好了。
Now do it--
oh, 100 more times.
现在就做——
哦，再100次。
- Yeah!
- 是的！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Ow!
噢！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Oh, Squiddy,
you're a genius.
-哦，鱿鱼，
你是个天才。
- Squidward, can the game
be over now?
- 章鱼哥，可以玩游戏吗
现在结束了吗？
All this pain is
starting to hurt.
这一切的痛苦都是
开始受伤。
- Oh, sorry.
There's no way to end the game
- 哦，抱歉。
没有办法结束游戏
without one of you winning.
你们中没有人获胜。
[both groan]
[两人都呻吟]
- Ready...set...go!
- 准备...开始...出发！
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[gasps]
[喘气]
[spits]
[吐口水]
Squidward, are you sure
we're doing this right?
章鱼哥，你确定吗？
我们这样做对吗？
These running shoes are
really hurting my ankles.
这双跑鞋是
真的很伤我的脚踝。
- Oh, you're absolutely
doing it right.
- 哦，你绝对是
做对了。
Try to pick up the pace,
though.
努力加快步伐，
不过。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Comin' through!
来了！
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
- I wanna play, Daddy.
- 我想玩，爸爸。
- No, son.
We're sports "fans."
- 不，儿子。
我们是体育“粉丝”。
We just watch.
我们只是看着。
- And...time.
- 还有……时间。
[both panting]
[两人都气喘吁吁]
Let's see those ankles.
让我们看看那些脚踝。
[ankles thumping]
[脚踝重击]
- [gasps]
Oh, yeah, those look bad.
- [喘气]
哦，是的，那些看起来很糟糕。
You both get--
mm, 50 points.
你们俩都会得到——
毫米，50分。
Why not?
- Hey, then we're still tied!
为什么不呢？
- 嘿，那我们还是打平了！
[marching band music]
[行进乐队音乐]
*
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
*
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
[buzzing]
[嗡嗡声]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[both screaming]
[两人尖叫]
- [screams]
- [sobbing]
- [尖叫]
- [抽泣]
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
- Hmm. Hmm.
- 唔。唔。
Where is it!
Where is it?
它在哪里！
它在哪里？
Hmm. Ah-ha!
There's my box of sports gear.
唔。啊哈！
这是我的运动装备盒。
It must've fallen
off the mail truck.
一定是掉下来了
从邮车上下来。
But what happened
to all the equipment?
但发生了什么事
到所有设备？
[bell dings]
[crowd cheering]
[铃声]
[人群欢呼]
What was that?
那是什么？
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
Huh?
啊？
[both groaning]
SpongeBob, what's going on?
[两人都呻吟]
海绵宝宝，这是怎么回事？
- Oh, hey--Sandy.
[both grunting]
- 哦，嘿 - 桑迪。
[两人都咕哝着]
Patrick and I are--
[grunts]
帕特里克和我是——
[咕哝]
in the middle
of a sports game.
在中间
的一场体育比赛。
- [grunts]
- This sure don't look
- [咕哝]
- 这看起来肯定不像
like any sport
I've seen before.
像任何运动一样
我以前见过。
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- I believe it's called
kickboxing, or something?
- 我相信它叫
跆拳道什么的？
- Well, whatever it is, it seems
to be causing you lots of pain.
- 好吧，不管是什么，看起来
给你带来很多痛苦。
- Ow!
Sure is.
- 噢！
当然是。
Ooh!
哦！
- Why not stop playing it
if it hurts so bad?
- 为什么不停止玩它
如果疼得那么厉害吗？
- We can't stop...
- 我们无法停止...
[panting]
Until we break our tie.
[气喘吁吁]
直到我们打破领带。
- Says who?
- 谁说的？
[musical fanfare]
[音乐号角]
- It's the rule giver.
- 这是规则的制定者。
[all murmuring]
[大家窃窃私语]
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
- I ain't never heard
of a rule giver.
- 我从来没听说过
一个规则的制定者。
- I prefer
"King of Sports,"
- 我更喜欢
“运动之王”
but you can never tell what will
catch on with the small folk.
但你永远不知道会发生什么
与小人物相处。
- You're making up a game
where SpongeBob and Patrick
- 你正在编一个游戏
海绵宝宝和派大星在那里
hurt themselves,
and you won't let them stop?
伤害自己，
你不让他们停下来吗？
- I'm just giving the people
what they want.
- 我只是给人们
他们想要什么。
- That's pretty low, Squidward,
even for you.
- 这相当低了，章鱼哥，
即使是为了你。
I'm putting a stop to this.
我要制止这一切。
SpongeBob and Patrick
have had enough!
海绵宝宝和帕特里克
已经受够了！
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
- See?
They're fine.
- 看？
他们很好。
Let the games resume.
让比赛继续进行吧。
- [grumbles]
[crowd cheering]
- [抱怨]
[人群欢呼]
Oh, I don't think so.
哦，我不这么认为。
Y'all want to see a game?
Fine.
你们想看比赛吗？
美好的。
Squidward, I challenge you
to a game--
章鱼哥，我向你挑战
来一场比赛——
a game of basketball.
一场篮球比赛。
Winner decides the fate
of SpongeBob and Patrick.
胜者决定命运
海绵宝宝和帕特里克。
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
Huh?
[crowd murmuring]
啊？
[人群窃窃私语]
Me? Play sports?
我？做运动吗？
No, no. I'm mostly
in an advisory position.
不，不。我主要是
担任顾问职务。
- Aw, come on!
We came to see some action.
- 噢，来吧！
我们是来看一些行动的。
Play the squirrel!
玩松鼠吧！
all: Play the squirrel!
Play the squirrel!
全体：扮演松鼠！
玩松鼠吧！
- See you on the court,
Your Highness.
- 球场见
殿下。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[moans]
[呻吟声]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Hey, Squidward,
one more thing.
- 嘿，章鱼哥，
还有一件事。
We're playing
San Antonio rules.
我们正在玩
圣安东尼奥规则。
- San "A-what-io" rules?
- San“A-what-io”规则？
- Check.
- [grunts]
- 查看。
- [咕哝]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[crowd cheering]
[人群欢呼]
- Oh, that was a foul.
- 哦，那是犯规。
- Tell it to yo Mama,
Squidward.
- 告诉你妈妈，
章鱼哥。
- Mama?
- 妈妈？
- Don't want to hear it.
- 不想听。
- Next round's soccer.
- 下一轮的足球比赛。
- What the what?
- Sure.
- 什么什么？
- 当然。
Every time you score,
you pick a new sport.
每次你进球的时候，
你选择一项新运动。
I thought you knew
all the rules, Squidward.
我以为你知道
所有规则，章鱼哥。
- Well, uh, yeah, well,
of course I do. Yeah.
- 呃，呃，是的，好吧，
我当然知道。是的。
- Good, then block this.
- 好，那就阻止这个。
[cheers and applause]
- Block what?
[欢呼和掌声]
- 阻止什么？
- Ha!
- 哈！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- Oh, come on,
I wasn't even ready.
- 哦，来吧，
我什至还没准备好。
- No time outs.
Football round!
- 没有超时。
足球赛！
[horn blares]
[喇叭声]
[growling]
- [screams]
[咆哮]
- [尖叫]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
[panting]
Just give me a second to--
[气喘吁吁]
请给我一点时间——
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[playful music]
[俏皮的音乐]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
[horn blares]
[喇叭声]
*
[grunts, babbles]
[咕哝声，胡言乱语]
*
[groans]
[呻吟]
- And the winner is...
Sandy Cheeks.
- 获胜者是...
桑迪脸颊。
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- Good game, Squidward.
- 好游戏，章鱼哥。
- Ow, ow, ow.
- 噢，噢，噢。
- Wow, Sandy.
That was amazing.
- 哇，桑迪。
太棒了。
- Yeah, I liked the part
- 是的，我喜欢这个部分
where you did that thing
with the ball and stuff.
你在哪里做那件事
与球和其他东西。
- [laughs]
Thanks, boys.
- [笑]
谢谢，孩子们。
Looks like we're
all done here.
看来我们是
一切都在这里完成。
That goes for you too.
I'm ending your game.
这也适合你。
我要结束你的游戏了
- [gulps]
But we're still tied.
- [吞咽]
但我们仍然是绑在一起的。
- Don't worry,
I'm declaring you both winners.
- 别担心，
我宣布你们俩都是赢家。
both: Yeah! We're winners!
We're winners! We're winners!
两人：是啊！我们是赢家！
我们是赢家！我们是赢家！
- Aww, don't worry,
Squidward.
- 哇，别担心，
章鱼哥。
[all groaning]
You're a winner too.
[全都呻吟]
你也是赢家。
- I hate winning.
- 我讨厌获胜。
Ow.
噢。
[quirky music]
[古怪的音乐]
*